SHINTOHO COMPANY , LTD .
A human life
Is naught
But two score and ten years
JIGOKU ( HELL )
A MITSUGU OKURA PRODUCTION
Original Concept by SOSUKE KASANE
Screenplay by NOBUO NAKAGAWA and ICHIRO MIYAGAWA
Cinematography by MAMORU MORITA
Lighting by HIROSHI ISHIMORI Sound by KIHACHIRO NAKAI
Production Design by HARUYASU KUROSAWA
Music by CHUMEI WATANABE
Edited by TOSHIO GOTO
Assistant Director : KEINOSUKE TSUCHIYA
Starring :
SHIGERU AMACHI , UTAKO MITSUYA , YOICHI NUMATA
HIROSHI HAYASHI , JUN OTOMO , AKIKO YAMASHITA
KIYOKO TSUJI , FUMIKO MIYATA , TORAHIKO NAKAMURA
KIMIE TOKUDAIJI , AKIKO ONO , TOMOHIKO OTANI , KOICHI MIYA
SAKUTARO YAMAKAWA , REI ISHIKAWA , HIROSHI SHINGUJI , HIROSHI IZUMIDA
Directed by NOBUO NAKAGAWA
A handsome youth in the morning ,
once lured by that merciless wind , is by dusk a heap of bones .
In the end , all must die .
Countless people have sinned on their way towards death .
Could the law even begin to punish them all ?
Some may slip through the law 's net ,
but they cannot elude their own consciences .
Religion dreams of a world where sinners
are punished after death for sins unpunished during life .
That world is Hell .
This is a tale of things
Not of this world
A tale of the River Sanzu
The eternal limbo of dead children
CONCEPTS OF HELL
Buddhism is not alone in positing the existence of hell .
Zoroastrianism , Christianity , and Islam , among others ,
all share similar beliefs .
In India , the idea arose together with that of reincarnation ,
even before Buddhism appeared
and evolved into the concept I just mentioned .
The Sanskrit word for hell , naraka ,
comes from the word for " abominable " or " excruciating . "
The Japanese adapted this word as naraku .
That guy from last night is dead .
Really ? He 's dead ?
So what if he is ?
Tamura !
By the way , congratulations . You and Yukiko are finally engaged .
I heard something interesting
about your future father-in-law , Professor Yajima .
In Japan , the most common conception is that of the " Eight Hells "
found in Buddhist sutras .
In fact , the number of sutras on the subject is enormous .
People call him a saint , but scratch the surface and you 'll find a dark past .
There 's a sin he wants to atone for .
It was during the war , in Malaya .
Just who is this Tamura ?
How can he be so awful ?
Can 't I get away from him somehow ?
Last night would have been the happiest night of my life
but for that damned accident .
Hello .
Professor and Mrs. Yajima , thank you very much .
You 'll see . I 'll make Yukiko happy .
Take good care of her , Shimizu .
Yes , sir .
Yukiko , I 'm so happy .
Thank you , Mother .
Mr. Shimizu ...
Yukiko 's our only child , and she 's a bit spoiled .
But with you we can rest easy .
Please look after her .
Study hard , and be a scholar in my husband 's footsteps .
I will .
Congratulations .
Tamura !
Surprised to see me ?
I 'd have rung the bell , but I was furious when you turned me away last time .
Anyway , congratulations .
We should have a drink to celebrate .
But uninvited guests shouldn 't stay too long , so I 'll be going .
I came to return this .
Shimizu , I 'll give you a ride .
Mrs. Yajima , your clock 's stopped .
They say that 's a bad omen .
Good night .
Don 't be a fool . Take it .
You 're behind on rent and tuition .
I like you , man .
I know everything .
You 've been sleeping with Yukiko .
I 'll bet she 's pregnant .
Could you turn there ?
- It 's a bad road . - I want to make a stop .
Look out !
Bastard ! You hit me !
Hey ! Goddamn you !
I 'm Tiger Kyoichi of the Gondo gang !
Kyoichi !
Kyoichi ! Are you all right ? Get up !
What happened ?
Tamura , stop the car ! You hit that guy !
I 'm not stopping , nobody saw us .
That drunk jumped in front of me .
That doesn 't matter . We hit him !
What ?
You made me take this road .
It wasn 't my fault .
That man could be dead .
If he is , Tamura and I are murderers .
Is something wrong ?
No , it 's nothing .
I just couldn 't sleep last night .
Don 't overdo it .
Stop by tonight . Yukiko 's expecting you .
CONCEPTS OF HELL
Kyoichi !
Mother .
You sure you didn 't see who did it ?
Shut up !
I said I didn 't know !
Damn it !
When I find who did this ...
" At 9pm , in Kamiuma in Setagaya Ward , "
" Kyoichi Shiga , 34 , a leader of the Gondo gang , "
" was struck by a passing vehicle while inebriated "
" and died of a brain haemorrhage at a nearby hospital . "
" There were no witnesses . The driver remains unknown . "
So you want to turn me in for manslaughter ?
We 're the ones who killed him .
We caused it .
Let 's go together .
Please .
That might ease your conscience , but I 'm not interested .
It 'd be stupid .
He was drunk . He ran into the road .
It was basically suicide . Besides , he was just some yakuza scum .
He 's not worth the best years of our lives .
Leaving so soon ?
I turned your luck around . If I go down , you go with me .
IN MEMORIAM THE GONDO SYNDICATE
The gang paid for the funeral ,
but how will we get by now ?
Hey , Mum , you must 've seen the car that hit him .
You were out there .
No , I didn 't .
But Yoko ,
what would you do if you knew who did it ?
I 'd find the guy and kill him .
Look what he 's done to us .
I didn 't tell the police ,
but I saw the car .
Ten years ago
a truck killed my husband .
The driver didn 't even go to prison ,
while I lost my man .
Telling the cops won 't do a damn thing .
Yoko , you and I can avenge Kyoichi .
We can kill the guys who did it and not get caught .
We must .
Yukiko .
You really kept me waiting .
I just had to see you today .
Shiro ...
I 'm ...
Is something wrong ?
Yukiko , I ...
killed a man .
Listen .
There were two of them .
We 'll trace the license number .
We 'll kill them , no matter how long it takes .
Understood ? I thought so .
Let 's talk to my father .
He 'll surely think of something .
I can 't stay here .
Something 's chasing me .
Shiro , please stay calm .
There aren 't any taxis .
Taxis ?
Let 's walk to the station .
I don 't feel like taking a taxi .
The faster I get there , the better .
Please , forget the taxi .
I 'd really rather walk .
You 're acting like a child !
Get in .
Where to ?
The police station .
Please drive slowly .
Yukiko !
Shiro ...
I don 't want to die .
Yukiko !
Shimizu , it 'll be all right .
Everything hinges on fate .
Professor ...
if I hadn 't insisted on a taxi ...
I may as well have killed her myself .
Dear .
Mrs. Yajima .
You don 't belong here .
Go away , please .
Go away , please !
Mrs. Yajima !
Give Yukiko back to me .
Give her back !
Fumi !
Give back my daughter .
That 's right , suffer .
You were about to let your conscience sell me out .
Will you win , or will I ?
Stop it !
Don 't get so worked up .
Hey ,
have a drink with me .
I 've got the blues too .
Let 's dance .
I 'm Yoko . Who are you ?
Listen ,
why don 't we go somewhere else ?
I 'm going home .
No !
HOTEL YOSHINO
" Shiro Shimizu . "
It 's him .
He 's the one who killed Kyoichi .
Can I see you again tonight ?
Sure .
I 'm glad .
Be at the bar at 9 : 00 , okay ?
Don 't forget . 9 : 00pm .
It 's him . No mistake about it .
You 've got the stuff , don 't you ?
Yeah .
Kyoichi , it won 't be long .
I 'm going to settle the score .
Once I finish them off , I 'll come join you .
Mother 's condition critical . Come immediately . - Father .
TENJOEN
RETIREMENT HOME
The kindness
Of my father
And mother ...
You are ?
Oh , you 're Shiro from Tokyo !
Yes .
I 'm Kinuko . They took me in last year .
I see .
This way .
Mother ,
it 's Shiro .
Mother .
how 's Father ?
Stop it , silly man !
You know , your son 's pretty cute .
Such nice eyes .
I just might cheat on you .
I want to go back to Tokyo !
Cut the crap .
It 's no surprise , with me like this .
Auntie .
You 're Shiro , aren 't you ?
I 'm Sachiko . I sent the telegram .
How nice that he came !
Thank you .
Her father paints . They moved in next door last year .
He 's an old friend of your father 's .
Next door ?
I may not make it to Oshoro
Father .
Or Takashima
Ah , Shiro , you 're here .
Father .
Your mother 's a little better .
I 'm having a painting of Hell made for Jiganji Temple .
This is Ensai Taniguchi .
He paints well , but he drank himself to ruin
and ended up here .
Father , aren 't you taking your walk this morning ?
Morning .
You 're up early , Detective .
Almost done , eh ?
So this is where all the bad people go , eh , Sachiko ?
Ensai , you got an answer for me yet ?
The answer 's no .
I won 't give Sachiko to a man like you .
Is that right ?
Ensai ...
aren 't you wanted for fraud in Osaka ?
The prefectural police called
about a forged painting .
Are you going to arrest me ?
They 'd make a fine couple !
And a cop in the family could come in handy , right ?
Let 's do this :
When the picture 's done , we 'll all have a long talk .
Dr. Kusama , the old man 's gotten worse !
Please come quickly ! - If I must .
- Hurry ! - Yeah , yeah .
- Quickly , Doctor ! - I know !
The doctor 's here .
It 's not just him , Doctor . We 're all weak .
It 's the food here .
You 're skimming our welfare payments .
Who 's skimming ?
The welfare office gives us 62 yen a day .
We spend 70 .
The food 's plenty nutritious .
Sachiko .
You 're going to marry me , right ?
Let go ! Please !
You like Sachiko , don 't you ?
The evening is clear The autumn wind blows
Bell crickets cry In the moonlight
The sky above my hometown
How fare my mother and father
Shiro !
You scared me to death !
I thought you got hit .
You did ?
I saw you walking absent-mindedly along the tracks .
You 've been here four days now .
Your mother seems a little better .
I 'd given up hope .
She said she 'd take me to Tokyo when she got better .
I 'm really looking forward to that .
Tamura !
Long time no see .
I thought I 'd drop by and see how you 're doing .
What did you do after I left ?
I 'll be going home now .
The spitting image of Yukiko , huh ?
The Yajimas are a bit better .
He said they 'd stop here on a lecture tour .
They 'll probably arrive tonight .
Tamura , please ! Go back to Tokyo immediately .
Stay away from me !
I 'll be at that inn over there .
I plan to stay a while .
See you .
Shiro !
Your mother 's taken a sudden turn for the worse .
Wait !
You 're returning to Tokyo if she dies , right ?
Take me with you ! Please !
Mother !
I bow in homage to the Buddha
I sing in praise of Bodhisattva Jizō
This is a tale of things
Not of this world
Hey , Professor Yajima and his wife are here .
Professor .
Mrs. Yajima .
Shimizu , there 's no need to say anything .
Let 's make a fresh start .
Yukiko !
Dr. Kusama ...
I may be small-time , but I 'm still a journalist .
What did Mrs. Shimizu die of ?
Angina pectoris .
What 's that supposed to mean ?
Are you suggesting my diagnosis was wrong ?
I demand an apology !
You 're wrong .
What ?
Who the hell are you ?
Mrs. Shimizu died from malpractice .
You knew your diagnosis was wrong ,
but a second opinion was too much bother .
What ?
That 's not true !
It was Gozo who killed Ito !
Father !
Cavorting with his mistress with his wife sick in the next room !
Ito and I were once lovers .
He stole her from me ! - I what ?
Everyone knows that !
Impudent parasite !
What ?
Fool !
You inhuman wretch ! Have you no shame ?
That heartless shit !
Idiot !
Have no fear , Doctor .
You 're not the only murderer here .
- Who did I kill ? - Silence !
Everyone here is complicit in murder .
What the hell are you talking about ?
Even you , Detective Hariya .
Last summer you took a bribe to frame a man .
He was so ashamed he killed himself .
Mr. Akagawa ,
you killed a man with an inaccurate article .
I did not !
I went to him and apologized ! But he was ...
Already dead .
Next we have the godlike director
of this charmingly shabby old folks ' home ,
the Tenjoen , or " Heavenly Garden . "
Not content with this pretty mistress ,
he has another in town ,
the plump owner of the Tonchuken Tavern .
Tamura , that 's enough !
And you , Professor ! What about your comrades in Malaya ?
Sir !
Old Tome 's dead !
You two killed him !
All you think about is the damn tenth anniversary festival !
TENJOEN RETIREMENT HOME TENTH ANNIVERSARY FESTIVAL
Day after day
This world fades Into the distance
Year after year
My death draws ever closer
Today is the funeral
Of another
Tomorrow
It will be mine
They look delicious !
Are they safe ?
At least they 're cheap , Doctor .
And they haven 't gone bad yet .
I don 't need a food poisoning scandal .
Who cares ?
They 're for the old folks , not us .
Always putting others first !
HIT-AND-RUN VEHICLE IDENTIFIED FROM SKID MARKS
My father insists I go into town for some paint .
I should be back tonight .
Sorry to leave when it 's so busy .
Did Mr. Tamura leave ?
Yes .
And I 'm returning to Tokyo with Professor Yajima tomorrow .
So soon ?
I wanted you to take Father and me hiking along Kiyosawa Gorge .
You 're no fun .
Is this a love scene ?
Here I was planning to sneak off alone with Shiro .
You like him , don 't you ?
Me , I love this man !
Shiro , which one of us do you like ?
Sachiko ?
Excuse me .
See you later .
Shiro , won 't you go with me ?
I forgot earlier . Are you Shiro Shimizu ?
This is for you .
Who 's it from ?
I just had to see you .
I 've come all the way here .
Shiro , please meet me on the rope bridge .
Yoko .
It 's been a while , Shiro .
You know my name ?
Of course .
I know everything about you .
I was Kyoichi Shiga 's woman . He 's the man you hit and killed .
His mother saw the whole thing .
We found you and Tamura right away .
Now I 've come ...
to kill you .
I was in love with you until I found out who you were .
Now I just want to kill you .
I 'm sorry .
Don 't do it . There 's plenty of time to die .
I knew this would happen . I know everything , you know .
Tamura ! Who are you ?
If it weren 't for you -
Just do as I say and you 'll be fine .
Tamura !
Tonight marks our anniversary .
We have little to offer , but please enjoy !
Mr. Shimizu , you pulled out all the stops !
You gave us fish with heads for a change !
HAPPY ANNIVERSARY ! THE TONCHUKEN TAVERN
Happy anniversary !
The tavern owner has given us a gift of their famous roast pork .
And I 'll sing for you too .
Poor singer that you are !
Let 's hear it for the boss lady !
Your attention , please !
All along the slopes
Of the mountain
The scything
Is finished
Special tonight , a kiss for everyone !
It 's a strip show !
No !
Sir , can 't we get some of those fish heads too ?
Yeah , where 's my head ?
Isn 't Tonchuken 's famous roast pork
a lot better than rotten fish ?
Eat that pork ! Drink that booze ! Pork ! Booze ! Booze !
Forgive my appearance , Professor .
Won 't you join us ?
Do you know where Shiro is ?
- I 'm afraid not . - Too bad .
Eat that pork ! Drink that booze ! Pork ! Booze ! Booze !
Who 's in there ?
Hey , what are you doing here ?
I 'll never let you go !
Mount Bandai in Aizu is a treasure mountain
Tied together , hugging tight
Hurry and grab that lovely girl
I 'm a plum blossom on the Mamuro River
Is Sado Island
A nice place to live
Sachiko !
Kusatsu 's a nice place Come pay a visit
Flowers blossom even in the hot springs
Kinuko !
I knew it ! I just knew it !
Don 't act so surprised .
I 'm sick of being your plaything out here in the boonies .
That 's it !
I 'll kill you both !
Father , it was all my fault !
You son of a bitch !
Stop it ! Don 't kill him !
This was my doing !
Damn you !
Father !
You whore !
Shiro , keep your mouth shut .
Go back and sit down as if nothing happened , okay ?
Professor .
Thank you for everything .
If we leave now , we can catch the last train home .
I see .
Professor !
Yukiko !
Let 's go .
Hey , more sake ! Bring more sake !
You want sake ? I have some .
Who are you ?
A relative of a former resident of the home .
I came to help celebrate .
How about a drink for everyone ?
It 's not poisoned , is it ?
What a thing to say !
I 'll drink some first to show it isn 't .
- Fine , pour me some . - Allow me .
Even those in the prime of life
Have suddenly died
With the coming of dawn
Tonight they lay their heads
On their pillows
But when morning comes ...
If you 'll allow me , I 'll test this for poison .
Well , one last drink .
Cheers !
Tamura !
Shiro , it 's terrible ! The Yajimas threw themselves in front of the train !
Tamura ! You son of a bitch !
You killed my son Kyoichi !
You pushed Yoko off that bridge !
I know everything !
I 'll kill you !
Bastards !
Those fish were rancid !
Shiro .
Tamura !
What is this place ?
This place ?
This is the path to Hell ,
the border between life and death .
This is the River Sanzu .
You and I
are going to Hell together .
You hear that crying ?
Listen .
It 's a baby crying .
It 's calling you .
Calling me ?
Why is it calling me ?
Tamura , tell me !
Where am I ?
I am Enma , King of Hell .
I am lord of the Eight Hells of Fire
and the Eight Hells of Ice .
I sit in judgment of all who slither into the underworld
and pass sentence on their sins .
Shiro Shimizu ,
recall now your multitude of crimes .
Look into the all-revealing mirror .
Bastard ! You hit me !
You are sentenced to the torments of the Eight Hells !
The first pile of stones
Is for their fathers
The second pile of stones
Is for their mothers
The third pile of stones
Is for brothers and sisters back home
Thus they pray for the happiness
Of those left behind
By day they play
Alone with their stones
There 's a baby crying .
It 's calling me .
Where 's it coming from ?
The demons of hell
Appear before them
And ask , " What is this you 're doing ? "
Where am I ?
This is the bank of the River Sanzu ,
where children are held in limbo for having died before their parents .
Your parents left behind in the world
Yukiko !
They do nothing but mourn your death
Forgive me !
It 's as if I killed you myself .
Forgive me .
The baby 's crying .
The baby with which we were blessed .
You ... were pregnant ?
I meant to tell you that night .
The crash killed both me and our child .
Yukiko ...
forgive me !
Forgive me !
Give our child a name .
It 's a girl .
The poor thing needs a name .
May I choose the name ? " Harumi . "
From the characters for " spring " and " beauty . "
Isn 't it pretty ?
Harumi .
So we had a child .
Oh , no !
I couldn 't raise her alone ,
so I set her on a lotus leaf on the river .
She 'll be swept away !
Swept away forever !
Hurry and save her !
Harumi !
I can 't go any further . You must look after her alone .
We go together , no matter where it takes us .
The baby 's being swept away .
Put my grave right next to yours ,
and find the best spot to bury my parents .
Shiro !
Yukiko !
Harumi !
A life is naught but two score and ten years .
Here meet the Six Paths of Existence .
You who have no home in the Three Unenlightened Worlds ,
as punishment for your sins in the world of the living ,
must wander aimlessly along these six paths .
Harumi !
Have you seen my child ?
Professor !
Mrs. Yajima !
Shimizu !
We had a child !
Where did she float away to ?
My daughter ...
Yukiko !
Professor , Mrs. Yajima ...
forgive me .
If it weren 't for me , none of this misery
would have come to pass .
Forgive me .
Give me back my daughter !
Fumi ! Stop that !
Shimizu , we too have descended into Hell .
Professor !
Yukiko 's death drove my wife mad .
We chose to die .
Professor , we meet again .
It was your fate to fall down to Hell .
Here 's another reason :
In Malaya you stole a comrade 's last sip of water .
You killed him .
It 's true !
He 's right !
That 's my canteen ! It 's mine !
I killed a man !
Yamaguchi .
Water !
Give me water !
Give me water .
You who are dead ,
if it 's water you want , drink your fill .
This is the pus wrung from your festering carcasses
and a cesspool of your foul wastes .
Drink all you wish !
You bastard ! You killed me !
I 'm sorry !
I 'll strangle you !
Die ! Die !
Harumi !
You killed me !
I 'm sorry . Forgive me .
Forgive me !
Quiet ! I don 't want to hear it !
You who are dead ,
this is the First Hell .
Here flesh is peeled , bones crushed , eyes plucked out and limbs severed .
Every time you make a sound
or even a whimper ,
you are returned to life to face the torments of Hell again .
Kinuko !
You were negligent as a doctor .
You made countless misdiagnoses without a shred of shame .
You were a slave to money and debauchery .
You will be sawed to pieces .
As a policeman you were supposed to protect the law-abiding ,
yet you were driven only by self-interest .
You implicated a man in a crime he didn 't commit .
Your hands will be cut off .
You were the most atrocious of all , the epitome of corruption .
Your sins outnumber the stones along the River Sanzu .
You will suffer each and every torment of Hell .
First you will be flayed .
Take me away from here , Shiro !
I loved you the minute I saw you !
Kinuko !
Father !
- Whore ! - Let me go !
You bitch !
Let go of me !
Bitch !
Father !
Shiro ,
you 're to come with me .
You will dwell with me in this dark hell forever .
No ! I want to live !
My baby 's crying !
She 's calling me !
You still don 't understand ?
You 're a fool .
Loving someone , worrying about them , suffering for them ...
All useless now !
You tried to sell me out for their sake .
For their sake you committed one sin after another .
This all happened due to you and your meddling !
Do you think you can escape from Hell ?
Just try it !
This is the Lake of Blood ,
to which those guilty of adultery , lust , license and lechery
are condemned for their immoral conduct .
Shiro !
I won 't let you go !
Let go !
I may not make it to Oshoro
Or Takashima
Shiro !
Yukiko ! Harumi !
Help me !
Sachiko !
Father !
Mother !
Sachiko !
I can 't see a thing .
Have I gone blind ?
Sachiko .
Have you seen my father ?
Your father ?
It seems I saw him somewhere ...
but I 'm not sure .
Why do you suffer so ?
If only we 'd met sooner in life .
Now it 's all too late .
It 's not ! I 'm going to live !
You 're right . It 's not too late .
Even now you want to touch her .
It 's not too late for that .
Shiro , take her in your arms .
Kiss her ! Then you 'll become just like me ,
one of Hell 's vermin !
No ! Don 't !
Mother !
You 're holding your sister .
That 's your younger sister !
Sachiko , Shiro 's your elder brother !
These hands !
The blood flowing in these hands is cursed !
When I went to live with your father ,
I was already pregnant with Ensai 's child .
Ito ! You mean ...
So Shiro is my son ?
Yes .
I 've lied to you both all these years .
Ito !
If anyone 's to blame , it 's you !
If only I 'd known !
I wouldn 't have turned into a drunkard .
This is fun ! I like you half-wits more all the time !
Let 's go .
Brother , wait .
Your baby !
Hurry and save your baby !
I hear her !
Wherever you go , you go with me .
You can 't escape from me !
Mr. Tamura , what do you want from my brother ?
You 're a demon ! You 're the accursed god of death !
Leave us alone !
That 's right . I 'm a demon .
I 'm the god of death .
Shiro !
Come with me !
Leave my brother alone !
Come on !
Tamura ,
you sold the most precious thing a man can possess :
You gave your conscience over to evil .
Those who sign away their conscience
suffer all the torments of bottomless Hell .
Harumi !
Shiro , help me !
The pain !
Hear me !
You who in life piled sin upon sin
will be trapped in Hell forever .
Suffer ! Suffer !
This vortex of torment will whirl for all eternity .
Help me !
Save me !
Shiro !
Save your child now , or she will suffer
endless torment in Hell .
You will be given this one final chance .
Hell ! This is Hell !
Harumi !
Yukiko !
Shiro , save Harumi !
Brother !
A human life
Is naught
But two score and ten years
Shiro !
Brother !